TYLER CHONG

TYLERCHONG9641@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

Experienced Web Developer with more than 7 years of demonstrated history of work in the web agency and tech startup industry.

Always curious and eager about gaining more knowledge in modern-day web and software technologies and beyond, to create eye-catching experiences and solve real-world problems.

EDUCATION

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Apr 2011 - Oct 2013, Hong Kong

Master of Science in Information Technologies

- Software Engineering
- Cyber Security

University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

Apr 2005 - Oct 2009, Hong Kong

Bachelor of Science in Information Technologies

- Computer Science
- Software Engineering
- OOP(Object-oriented programming) languages
- Cyber Security

SKILLS

Web Programming: React, Redux, Next, Gatsby, Node, Express, TypeScript, JavaScript, Pixel-Perfect|Responsiveness(HTML, CSS, Sass, Less, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS)

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon DynamoDB, Firebase, Redis

APIs: Social Media, Google APIs, Web API/JSON/SOAP, OAuth, GraphQL/REST API

Testing: Unit Testing, E2E Testing

Platforms: Linux, MacOS, Windows, Docker

Tools: Git, IDE, Amazon Web Service, Azure DevOps

Ecommerce: WordPress, Shopify

EXPERIENCE

Wealthsimple, Toronto - Full Stack Developer

February 2019 - April 2021

- Handled the full-stack development on the Wealthsimple for the Advisors product (Wealthsimple's B2B offering that enables financial advisors to focus on delivering value to their clients).
- Implemented white labeling: a key player to our internal design system of themeable React components, eliminating theme-related bugs.
- Implemented the associate role: this feature saves advisors time by allowing them to invite colleagues to securely manage their clients.
- Rewrote the "log in as client" functionality ("impersonation"): the feature allows advisors to perform actions on behalf of their clients the way the client would themselves.

Mitre Media, Toronto - Full Stack Developer

February 2018 - January 2019

- Reduced server response time significantly using different caching strategies, assets management, and database querying optimization in MySQL.
- Architected and implemented a front end system for React Application with Material UI and Styled Components and animation using React Pose.
- Incorporated ReactJS strategies such as higher-order components, render props, and global state management using Apollo client caching.
- Proposed and developed GraphQL endpoint for its advantage of a single source of data while developing GraphQL schema foundation in Rails and reusable Querying/Mutation structure in React.

Uberflip, Hong Kong - Remote Full Stack Developer

January 2017 - November 2017

- Administered a reusable in-house web app to process issues and commit
 data from Redmine and Jira for SR&ED review using a pure JavaScript
 solution.
- Promoted code quality and standards by implementing various custom Git
- Employed PHP mass detector and PHP linting tools to maintain code integrity and visibility among the development team.

FLYDESK, Hong Kong - Full Stack Developer

January 2014 - December 2016

- Implemented a redesigned version of the public website.
- Created multiple landing pages with reusable components.
- Created responsive emails with MJML for use in Drip campaigns.
- Analyzed data in Google Analytics and provided new insights.
- Implemented a signup gateway with the main app, with Google and Facebook social sign-in.

SOCIAL PROFILES

Github: https://github.com/hectorstudio

Portfolio: http://tylerchong.herokuapp.com/